Mounir KHEBBAZA

29 ans 888 rue Wellington, Montreal, QC CANADA

mounir.khebbaza@gmail.com +33615314697 Driving license

Canada: Discovering a new culture

Graduated from a French engineer school in 2013, my first experiences allowed me to touch a pretty large variety of technologies, from system administration to web developer. I can handle tasks in production and operation chain of a company's information system thanks to those experiences.

My curiosity helps me to better appreciate new tools. Today, I want to use those multiple skills and my taste for innovation to keep progressing in jobs while developing ambitious tools.

This curiosity pushed me to discover a new way of life both professionally and personally. I chose to come to Canada for everything it can offer humanly and culturally.

Work experiences

From October 2018 - Web developer - National Bank of Canada

The role of the department where I work is to detect banking frauds. We build a centralized application able to gather information (banking transactions, users' actions, ...) coming from different applications. This tool computes this information and with heuristics (implemented code) triggers alert when it detects a fraudulent behavior.

Technologies: PHP, Laravel, VueJS, MariaDB, Docker, Openshift, Git, Jenkins, Logstash, Redis, Kafka

From April 2017 to October 2018 – Web developer (Tech leader) – Digital Effervescence

In a start-up company specialized in digital marketing, I am a web developer. I used skills I got from my former job to build a CI/CD platform, a developing environment, some structure in the way of coding. Those processes allow us to better handle operation and production chain.

Moreover, I learnt a lot about digital marketing and marketing automation tools (such as Mautic).

Technologies: PHP, Symfony3, Wordpress, Prestashop, Docker, Composer, Git, API Graph de Facebook, Mautic, MailChimp, Openshift

From January 2017 to March 2017 - DevOps engineer and Web developer - Nalys

I joined a Belgian company in January 2017. This company provides services (websites implementation, consulting, ...) to customers. My role was to find and configure tools to better appreciate developing, testing, and production processes. I

also developed a tool allowing HR to list all employees' skills. This tool helps them to find the best match, the best candidate for a project.

From this experience, I started to learn CI/CD and Docker technologies.

Technologies: Docker, Vagrant, Virtualbox, Jenkins, Open-shift, Maven, Composer, Nexus, AngularjS, Symfony3

From October 2013 to December 2016 - Web developer - ERDF (Solutec)

I offered services to the French electricity supplier for 3 years. I was in two different teams. I was one of the developer of a monitoring platform. The goal of this platform was to help non-technical (in IT Infrastructure) to understand and follow the state of applications (such as accounting, customers' electricity consumption, ...). This platform offers dashboards with operational data.

Technologies: API REST, PHP (framework YII), Python (framework Flask), Javascript (JQuery, Ajax), Perl, SH, HTML5, CSS3 (Bootstrap), Apache, MySQL, Unix, Windows.

In the other team, I was in charge of (infrastructure and development) an application called inventory. Its objective was to collect all server data (CPU and RAM consumption, software installation, licenses, DB instances, ...). The data was gathered in a CMDB.

I started to learn Python and improve my skills in scripting programming.

Technologies: PERL, SH, PowerShell, XSLT, JSON, XML, Python (Socket et Requests), REST, PHP, Apache, PostgreSQL, Oracle, MongoDB, Unix (RHEL, AIX, SunOS), Windows.

From September 2010 to September 2013 – Web developer intern - ST Microelectronics

Within a team composed of microelectronic engineer, my role was to make repetitive tasks automatic. This experience was a rewarding experience, my first as an engineer, I consolidate my Linux and scripting skills. But what I liked the most was to mix two different domains: IT and microelectronic (platforms for smartphone).

Technologies: Linux, Serveur Apache, DB (PostgreSQL), PHP, HTML5 et CSS3, MVC, Javascript, PERL, Excel

From June to September 2012 - Web developer intern - Connect.ie (Dublin)

I joined this Irish company in June 2012. My role was to rebuild the website of this company. The objective of this website is to explain people medical terms (diseases) using synonyms / barbarisms.

Technologies: PHP, JS (JQuery), HTML, CSS, Apache, SEO, Drupal CMS, MySQL, linux Centos.

From April to June 2010 - IT tech intern - BSO

My role was to completely automate server configuration before installing it in the customer's company.

Technologies: Powershell, Windows Server, Active Directory, Exchange.

Personal projects

June 2019 (3 days)

In order to learn new programming languages, I decided to build an application able to display my resume. I implemented the API using Golang, the frontend using React and I used MongoDB to store Json Document.

The next step will be to create a user profile. Every user wll be able to create his own resume. And finally, as a bonus, I would like to add more themes to make it customisable.

Technologies: Golang, React (Code Splitting avec React Loadable), MongoDB, Docker, Docker-Compose.

January 2019 - aujourd'hui

I have followed two courses, since January, to learn how to build video games. One of them is focusing on Unity 2D and the other one on Unreal Engine.

In those courses, I built different variety of games such as an escape game, an tower defence, a ball breaker and a space shooter.

Once trainings are over, I would like, with a friend of mine, to build my own game.

Technologies: Unity, Unreal Engine, C# et C++.

September 2018 (1 week)

To learn React and Redux, I got the idea of developing a tiny application using the Spotify API. This application is a albums and artists browser.

Next step will be to listen musics of a selected album.

Technologies: React, Redux et Spotify API.

March 2017 (4 days)

On march 2017, I start to develop a tool capable of listing employees of a company, their skills and every project they worked on. The goal of this tool is to help managers finding the perfect matching resources for a client needs.

I only developed the authentication and model parts of the application.

Technologies: API Symfony 3 (PHP), Angular2, OAuth, MySQL

Education

Networking and telecommunication engineer (master's degree) - CPE Lyon, France

DUT Networking and telecommunications (associate degree) - IUT Grenoble, France

Baccalauréat Scientific - Lycée Monge Chambéry, France

Others trainings and certificates: First Certificate in English - B2 level, Certification ITIL v3 information system processes, Microsoft Powershell and Python trainings.

Interests

Handball (5 years in competition), Football (9 years in competition)

New technologies, Video games

Movie theatre, reading et traveling